Guide to the College of Technology Records
University of Houston Libraries
College of Technology Records
1940-2009
2009-015
University of Houston. College of Technology
1.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
These records contain 2 boxes relating to the College of Technology at the University of Houston. Material includes booklets, flyers, reports, handbooks, manuals, and video tapes.
Historical Note:
The College of Technology had its beginnings in 1941 when local firms contributed funds for the third permanent building on campus for the new School of Technology. The first technical institute programs to be initiated by the new college in 1945 were also the first engineering technology programs in the state of Texas, accredited by the Engineers Council for Professional Development. By 1962 the College of Technology offered 16 programs - 9 vocational and 7 engineering technology programs. By 1968 the college was granting a Bachelor of Science in Technology degree.
Throughout the decades since the 1940s, the School of Technology has grown to meet the ever-changing disciplines associated with technology and the growing diversity of the student body. Today the college is comprised of three different departments and a wide range of disciplines. The Engineering Technology department has carried forth the engineering technology programs that were the hallmark of the college's early years, and now cover the areas of computer engineering, networks, construction management, electrical power and mechanical technology. The Human Development and Consumer Sciences department covers the areas of Consumer Merchandising and Human Resources Development and the Information and Logistics Technology department covers the areas of information technology, printing and computer graphics, logistics and technical leadership.
The College of Technology continues to revise and update its programs as technology changes and as the marketplace grows in its needs for competent, well-trained technologists. We are currently in the process of developing a new department in Life Sciences Technology based upon the expanding fields of biomedical engineering, bioinformatics and the expanding medical marketplace within the Houston area and around the world.
Source:
College of Technology website
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston. College of Technology
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
These records contain 2 boxes relating to the College of Technology at the University of Houston. Material includes booklets, flyers, reports, handbooks, manuals, and video tapes. This collection is arranged chronologically and alphabetically as necessary by the following series; booklets and flyers, and videos. Materials range in date from the 1940s to 2009.
Detailed List of Contents
- Printed Materials
  - Booklets and Flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Booklets and Flyers, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - A Study of the Effectiveness of summer workshops for beginning teachers of marketing and distributive education in Texas, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - An internship Program for Technical Vocational Teachers in Post-Secondary Schools 14 College of Technology Phase 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - College of Technology - Phase 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Compaction of Fiber Reinforced Concrete by Vibration and surface Pressure by Benjamin E. Lazar (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - CVAE Education Program (clerical and ODP) Research Project Final Report, June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Faculty evaluation System, May 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Final Report - A Project to rewrite and restructure the competitive events for the distributive education clubs of America, Texas Association (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Heat Load Manual (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Information Handbook, 1946-47, 9-1-46 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Information Handbook, 1947-48 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Learn Electronics/Electricity (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Parade of Careers (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Past Present Future, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Report of the College of Technology programming committee for the new College of Technology building, January 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stationary (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sophisticated Technologies in a University environment (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - UH University Park - Sophisticated Technologies in a University environment (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Videos
  - University of Houston College of Technology Slide Program (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - College of Technology Promotional Video - Produced and Directed by Michael Gibson, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - College of Technology Promotional Video - Coffer (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - UH College of Technology (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - University of Houston College of Technology Slide Program (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - University of Houston College of Technology, Slide Program, ID (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - University of Houston College of Technology (Box 2, Folder 7)